Guide to the Gee family papers, 1777-1973
Gee family papers, 1777-1973
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gee family papers, 1777-1973.
4176
Gee family.
1.2 cubic ft.
Orderly book, correspondence, photographs, a genealogy, a commission, a discharge, a land grant, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of the family of Thomas E. Gee, d.1796, who was quartermaster sergeant in Col. John Lamb's regiment of artillery, a detachment from which, commanded by Capt. Wool, was attached to Clinton's brigade during the Sullivan expedition.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Thomas E. Gee, d.1796, was quartermaster sergeant in Col. John Lamb's regiment of artillery, a detachment from which, commanded by Capt. Wool, was attached to Clinton's brigade during the Sullivan expedition.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Orderly book, Aug. 27-Oct. 26, 1779, of Sullivan's campaign kept by Thomas Gee; correspondence, 1803-1934, concerning Thomas Gee, taxes, and his heirs; transcription, photocopy, and photos of the orderly book; photocopies and photographs of Thomas Gee's military service record and other legal documents; Gee family genealogy and family tree; correspondence with historical societies, libraries, archives, and genealogical societies concerning the compilation of the Gee genealogy, from Henrietta Gee McFarlane; paper by Mrs. McFarland, "Frontier Fort,"; and photographs including Gee family gravestones and the graveyard at St. Andrew's Cemetery, Walden, N.Y., where many Gee family members were buried. Also, commission, discharge, and land grant, 1777-1790.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gee family.; Gee, Thomas E., d. 1796.; McFarlane, Henrietta Gee.; Daughters of the American Revolution. Major Molly Chapter.; United States. Army.; United States. Army--Order books.
Places:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--History--Sullivan's Indian Campaign, 1779.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Typed transcription of orderly book, 1779, Aug.-Oct. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photocopy of orderly book (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Photocopies of Thomas Gee documents (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Photocopies of Thomas Gee compiled military record (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New York in the Revolution (and other notes) on Thomas Gee and the Revolution (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photocopies of Thomas Gee military service record (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Chronology (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes on Thomas Gee and the compilation of his service record (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Artillery Officers (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Legal documents - Wills, etc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Thomas Gee - compilation of Revolutionary War service record (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Maps (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Thomas Gee's Land book (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Gee Genealogy and Family Tree (Box 1, Folder 17)
- The Gee family [ 1783 - ] Genealogy (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The family of Thomas Gee and other Gee's (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Thomas and Mary Gee (Box 1, Folder 20)
- NY Genealogical and Biographical Society; and National Genealogical Society (Box 1, Folder 21)
- NY Historical Society; NY Public Library (Box 1, Folder 22)
- NYS, Albany, NY (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Orange County (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Archives (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cortland County Historical Society - Mrs. Goetschous, Mrs. Paul (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cornell University and Hamilton College (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Latter Day Saints Genealogical Society, Salt Lake City (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photocopy of paper by Henrietta Gee McFarlane, "Frontier Fort" (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence about "Frontier Fort" (Box 2, Folder 7)
- D.A.R. - Washington (Box 2, Folder 8)
- D.A.R. - Major Molly Chapter (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Sons of the American Revolution (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Brandon, Katherine (Box 2, Folder 11)
- English Gee's (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Garr - Yeager - Weaver - Brown (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Gardner, Virginia (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Gee, Adelbert E(dward) - Kirkwood, NY (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hamner, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Hasbrouck, Kenneth E. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- McMaster, Harry (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Peterman, Fred E. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Wheeler, Mrs. Walter - Cincinnatus, NY (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Wyant, Willis (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence Index (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Secondary Research Material (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Orderly book, Aug. 27-Oct. 26, 1779, of Sullivan's Campaign, kept by Thomas Gee, quartermaster sergeant in Col. John Lamb's New York regiment of artillery, a detachment from which, commanded by Capt. Wool, was attached to Clinton's brigade during the expedition (Box 3)
- Correspondence 1803-1934, including:
  - Memorandum, 1886 [of Mr. Geo. W. Harris concerning Thomas Gee] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tax receipt for taxes paid by George Gee (Heirs of Thomas Gee) for 1800-1802 inclusive dated Albany 23rd June 1803 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Two letters, 1887, from Gen. John S. Clark to Geo. W. Harris relating to Thomas Gee (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letter, 1887, from Geo. S. Conover to Geo. W. Harris relating to the Orderly book (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letter of Mrs. Frank E. Gee, May 7, 1934, relating to Thomas Gee and the Gee family; with enclosures, 1934, of copies of 18th century records (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Also one clipping (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photographs of Graveyard at St. Andrew's Cemetery near Walden, NY where the Gee family was buried (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Photographs of John M. Olin Library, Cornell University; a coach, unidentified; and a house, unidentified (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photographs taken 1973 of Patent Clock; 1 taken 1957 of patent clock advertisement (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Photographs of orderly book (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Photographs of gravestone and graveyard of Thomas Gee (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Photographs of military service record documents (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Photographs of John M. Olin Library, Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Photographs of scenes including Lambert Hitchcock chair factory and Old Riverton Inn, taken 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Photographs taken Apr. 1975 of orderly book (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photographs of company muster roll and George Washington facsimile document (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Photographs of military service record documents (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Contact sheet (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Negatives (Box 4, Folder 14)